<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Kevin Richardson</title><link>http://magically.us/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://magically.us/feeds/all.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 19:34:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Reflections on My Transition to a Startup</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-07-22/reflections-on-my-transition-to-a-startup.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For approximately the past year, I worked as a web developer for a mid-sized company. Overall, the experience was pleasant. I got a chance to experiment with Django, JavaScript, and real-world web development; garner experience acquiring and completing the requirements of stakeholders; and meet some very intelligent and considerate people. However, I found myself feeling bored and constricted in the role as the needs of the company (at least in my position's capacity) were generally pretty low and undemanding. I could not wait until it was time to leave for the day and never felt terribly satisfied when I got home in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, when the founder of a local startup emailed me to ask if I would be potentially interested in working with his company, I was highly intrigued and agreed to meet with him and his co-founder to discuss the role. After our quick lunch, he invited me to a follow-up interview at the startup's offices to go into more detail how I would propose fulfilling the technological needs of the new company. A few days later, he extended an offer which I later accepted. My work at the startup began on July 1st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I've not yet been an employee of the company for too long, I've wanted to reflect on my experiences for the benefit of myself as well as those considering employment in a startup. The experience has been very positive thus far and certainly differs from that of the mid-sized company. What follow are a (non-exhaustive) few of the differences I've noticed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Greater Transparency&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world where various tiers of managers make decisions, it is often impossible to know the reasons behind various directives or the intended direction of the company. However, when a company is smaller, thoughts are often discussed by each employee before a decision is reached. Fortunately, I've been enjoying a sense of greater transparency in my company as each person is playing a pivotal role in its success. Instead of having managers whose schedules are entirely filled with meetings (and eventually discuss what needs to get done), I get to participate actively in the conversation of the product we are creating. This is very fun and refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;More Responsibility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the chance for increased dialogue and action does not come without consequence. Each person has a very important role to play and, thus, seems to have more responsibility than he would at a larger company. Having more responsibility doesn't phase me, however, as I enjoy getting to make many of the integral technical decisions and have a fun time pondering over what those decisions should be. Although I was permitted to make a few decisions at my last job, it was much harder to make the larger decisions as they had already been made and were entrenched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fusion of Responsibilities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides having to choose (and implement) the technical stack used by the company to bring its product to market, many other tasks need to be completed. Because the company is young (and still very small), each employee must be willing to help out whenever possible (even if it means listening to the plans of another and thinking through their strengths and weaknesses) and be willing to try things out of their comfort zones. I have found this is much more satisfying than doing the same thing each day and provides me a chance to learn and think about things I would not have otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article's intention is not to judge either type of company (or the ones at which I have worked in particular) as both have their merits and downfalls. Instead, I merely hope to shed light on issues I've encountered to hopefully guide someone contemplating employment at either type in the future. Regardless, do not forget these experiences are my own and it is highly unlikely yours would be identical.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 19:34:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-07-22:2013-07-22/reflections-on-my-transition-to-a-startup.html</guid><category>startups</category><category>employment</category></item><item><title>Items of the Week: July 1, 2013</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-07-07/iotw-july-1-2013.html</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://pingbin.com/2012/12/setup-wifi-raspberry-pi/"&gt;WiFi on your Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; -- Having recently acquired a &lt;a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/"&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, I was interested in connecting it to my LAN over WiFi so as to reduce cable clutter while being able to access it via SSH or X Forwarding. This article discusses a very low cost USB WiFi card as well as how to enable it. &lt;a href="http://www.savagehomeautomation.com/projects/raspberry-pi-installing-the-edimax-ew-7811un-usb-wifi-adapte.html"&gt;This guide&lt;/a&gt; was also very helpful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://dyhr.com/2009/09/05/how-to-enable-x11-forwarding-with-ssh-on-mac-os-x-leopard/"&gt;How to enable X11 Forwarding with SSH on Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; -- After enabling X11 Forwarding in the remote machine's &lt;code&gt;sshd_config&lt;/code&gt; file, login to the machine with &lt;code&gt;ssh -Y user@host&lt;/code&gt;. After login, run the desired command. Very awesome!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://pyohio.org/"&gt;PyOhio&lt;/a&gt; -- PyOhio is a free Python conference in Columbus, OH. This year, the event occurs on July 27th and 28th and has a plethora of interesting &lt;a href="http://pyohio.org/schedule/talks/list/"&gt;talks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://pyohio.org/schedule/tutorials/list/"&gt;tutorials&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 19:49:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-07-07:2013-07-07/iotw-july-1-2013.html</guid><category>iotw</category></item><item><title>Items of the Week: June 24, 2013</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-06-30/iotw-june-24-2013.html</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://newsblur.com/"&gt;Newsblur&lt;/a&gt; -- With &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2013/03/a-second-spring-of-cleaning.html"&gt;Google Reader's impending shutdown on July 1&lt;/a&gt;, I had a need to find a service for handling the RSS feeds to which I am subscribed. For a while, &lt;a href="http://cloud.feedly.com/#welcome"&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt; was intriguing but I eventually found myself wanting something more similar to the experience which &lt;a href="http://reederapp.com/"&gt;Reeder&lt;/a&gt; has offered to me over the past couple of years. To that end, &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5958407"&gt;this comment&lt;/a&gt; on Hacker News filled me with enough curiosity to subscribe to Newsblur for a year and I have not yet been disappointed. Although I'm not yet sure how much I will use the feature, Newsblur allows its users to share stories in a &lt;a href="http://kfr2.newsblur.com/"&gt;blurblog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://readkitapp.com/"&gt;Readkit&lt;/a&gt; -- ReadKit is an OS X application for reading saved content from a plethora of services, including &lt;a href="http://readability.com/"&gt;Readability&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://pinboard.in"&gt;Pinboard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://newsblur.com"&gt;Newsblur&lt;/a&gt;, and more. As it offers an interface very similar to Reeder, I have been greatly enjoying the application and look forward to consuming a large volume of information through it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://class.coursera.org/startup-001"&gt;Startup Engineering&lt;/a&gt; -- Startup Engineering is a Coursera course that "[covers] modern software engineering principles with a focus on mobile HTML5 development" and will bring the concepts to life by sharing real engineering problems from the work of "top Silicon Valley startups (including Uber, Coinbase, Meteor, Square, Stripe, AirBnb, Twilio, Taskrabbit, Judicata, Counsyl, Twitter, and Asana". I'm very excited to complete this course for both for its theory as well as the chance it provides to become more acquainted with &lt;a href="http://nodejs.org/"&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 17:13:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-06-30:2013-06-30/iotw-june-24-2013.html</guid><category>iotw</category></item><item><title>Items of the Week: June 10, 2013</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-06-17/iotw-june-10-2013.html</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.obeythetestinggoat.com/"&gt;Obey the Testing Goat&lt;/a&gt; -- This website for the forth-coming &lt;a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920029533.do?cmp=af-code-book-product_cj_9781449367794_7079286"&gt;Test-Driven Web Development with Python&lt;/a&gt; explores how one can effectively utilize Test-Driven Development while developing web applications with the &lt;a href="https://djangoproject.com"&gt;Django web framework&lt;/a&gt;. You may &lt;a href="http://chimera.labs.oreilly.com/books/1234000000754/index.html"&gt;view the book online&lt;/a&gt; to gain a better understanding of the topics it will cover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://mapstack.stamen.com/"&gt;Map Stack&lt;/a&gt; -- "Map Stack makes designing maps free, easy, and fun" and is currently available from 11am to 5pm PST (Monday to Friday). The service allows you to modify the different parts of the map stack (backgrounds, roads, labels, etc) using controls for color, opacity, brightness, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2013/06/16/Go-Love-Hate"&gt;Golang Diaries I&lt;/a&gt; -- Tim Bray discusses experiences he faces while learning the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go_(programming_language)"&gt;Go programming language&lt;/a&gt;. I'm also an advocate of his philosophy that "[...] a really good time to write about something is while you're still discovering it" and will strive to do so more frequently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 17:13:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-06-17:2013-06-17/iotw-june-10-2013.html</guid><category>iotw</category></item><item><title>Items of the Week: June 3, 2013</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-06-09/iotw-june-3-2013.html</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UYXqbkHMj6k"&gt;Processing payments for the paranoid&lt;/a&gt; -- In this recording of a talk from &lt;a href="http://2013.djangocon.eu/"&gt;DjangoCon EU 2013&lt;/a&gt;, Andy McKay shares discoveries he has made while creating the payment processing structure behind Mozilla's &lt;a href="https://marketplace.firefox.com/"&gt;Firefox Marketplace&lt;/a&gt;. Among other things, he advocates restricting access to payment provider credentials as much as possible (through several layers of services) because the largest source of vulnerability is often ourselves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i9MHigUZKEM"&gt;AngularJS Fundamentals in 60-ish Minutes&lt;/a&gt; -- This 70 minute video provides a fantastic introduction to &lt;a href="http://angularjs.org/"&gt;AngularJS&lt;/a&gt; and its various components. Furthermore, the creator suggests a project structure that helped me understand the components in more detail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/jmcunningham/AngularJS-Learning"&gt;AngularJS-Learning&lt;/a&gt; -- This GitHub repository contains links to various websites and other resources for learning AngularJS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://animal-crossing.com/newleaf/"&gt;Animal Crossing: New Leaf&lt;/a&gt; -- Although this Nintendo 3DS game has only been available since this morning at midnight, I'm having a great time and look forward to learning more about the inhabitants of my virtual island paradise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 19:21:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-06-09:2013-06-09/iotw-june-3-2013.html</guid><category>iotw</category></item><item><title>Items of the Week: May 27, 2013</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-06-02/iotw-may-27-2013.html</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://osrc.dfm.io/"&gt;The Open Source Report Card&lt;/a&gt; -- "Enter a GitHub username to see a dynamically generated progress report for their open source contributions." For example, &lt;a href="http://osrc.dfm.io/kfr2"&gt;my open source report card&lt;/a&gt; discusses my interest in Python as well as GitHub users who have similar work patterns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://gitray.com/"&gt;Gitray&lt;/a&gt; -- A webapp allowing the user to easily navigate projects hosted on GitHub via a file tray similar to that of Sublime Text. For an example, view the &lt;a href="http://gitray.com/kfr2/cmsplugin-biography"&gt;Gitray of cmsplugin-biography&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/wrobstory/folium"&gt;Folium&lt;/a&gt; -- A Python library for integrating with the &lt;a href="http://leafletjs.com/"&gt;Leaflet JavaScript library&lt;/a&gt; that produces mobile-friendly, interactive maps. The library supports filesets from OpenStreetMap, Mapbox, Stamen, and Cloudmade. Check out the project's page for a plethora of fantastic-looking example maps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/games/detail/zp2Ns75itEVaf0PoEIyv49f2MEBspSeA"&gt;Donkey Kong Country Returns 3D&lt;/a&gt; -- This game for the Nintendo 3DS is a revamp of the Wii's Donkey Kong Country Returns. I'm enjoying how the game takes very minimal investment (as the levels don't take very long to complete) while looking fantastic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 18:02:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-06-02:2013-06-02/iotw-may-27-2013.html</guid><category>iotw</category></item><item><title>Introducing cmsplugin-biography</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-05-28/introducing-cmsplugin-biography.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I've been exploring &lt;a href="https://www.django-cms.org/en/"&gt;django CMS&lt;/a&gt; to gain an understanding of how to use it to extend the fantastic &lt;a href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;Django web framework&lt;/a&gt; into a content management system that can be easily used by content managers. Overall, I have been incredibly impressed with the CMS and look forward to using it more in the future. Because the CMS is an extension to Django and consequently offers all the benefits of the web framework, it is very easy to integrate various extensions. If a current &lt;a href="https://www.django-cms.org/en/add-ons/"&gt;add-on&lt;/a&gt; does not meet a requirement, it is possible to implement &lt;a href="http://docs.django-cms.org/en/2.4.0/extending_cms/custom_plugins.html"&gt;custom plugins&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As my current project moves forward, I need to create various plugins for the CMS that allow content managers to refer to various kinds of dynamic, database-driven content. To that end, I've decided to start with an easy project: a plugin for the creation and display of biographies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/kfr2/cmsplugin-biography"&gt;cmsplugin-biography&lt;/a&gt; is a django CMS plugin that allows the user to create a biography of a person and refer to it within any number of pages. For example, a user may want to create biographies of his company's leadership team and refer to them across a variety of web pages. Instead of having to update a biography's text across multiple locations should something change, he will only need to update the biography once and the change will propagate across the pages on which the biography is located. Furthermore, each instance of the plugin allows the user to provide a "short description" that will override the global description attached to the selected biography. This is useful if, for instance, it is desirable to to provide a summary that links to another page containing the biography's full description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating the plugin didn't take much time and I am relatively pleased with the results. As I begin integrating it into a CMS-powered site over the coming weeks, I'll hopefully determine what features it is missing. Eventually, I'll be comfortable enough with the plugin to release it on &lt;a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi"&gt;PyPI&lt;/a&gt;. If you use the plugin and run into any issues or would like a feature added, please leave a comment on the plugin's &lt;a href="https://github.com/kfr2/cmsplugin-biography/issues"&gt;issues page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 21:44:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-05-28:2013-05-28/introducing-cmsplugin-biography.html</guid><category>python</category><category>django</category><category>django cms</category></item><item><title>Items of the Week: May 20, 2013</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-05-26/iotw-may-20-2013.html</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.django-cms.org"&gt;Django CMS&lt;/a&gt; -- My group has been tasked with conjoining my company's plethora of websites under a single, CMS-powered website to reduce confusion among customers and unify the company's branding presence. As many of the sites currently use the fantastic &lt;a href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; framework and the team greatly enjoys using it, we wanted to find an extension to the framework that would fit the needs of the project. To that end, Django CMS seems to fit the bill incredibly well. If interested, I suggest you &lt;a href="https://demo.django-cms.org/"&gt;try out Django CMS's demo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.zombiesrungame.com/"&gt;Zombies, Run!&lt;/a&gt; (5k Training) -- In this augmented reality app, you enter a postapocalytic world as Runner 5, an individual tasked with walking and running over a zombie-ridden landscape in search of supplies that allow your outpost to continue its existence. As mentioned on the app's website, "Over the course of an eight week, 25 workout training [program], you’re trained to help collect supplies and protect the town from the encroaching zombie apocalypse." The application syncs to Zombielink, a web app allowing you to view a plethora of information about your sessions, including distance covered, time ellapsed, and a map of the the route you've taken.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/37904/formula-d"&gt;Formula D&lt;/a&gt; -- A boardgame in which the players take on the role of professional racecar drivers pushing their vehicles to the limit "[...] on the most challenging tracks the world has ever seen." I've only played the game once so far but certainly look forward to future sessions. You might be interested in seeing the gameplay as &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iSYEoP0j63c"&gt;featured on TableTop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Call_of_the_Wild"&gt;Call of the Wild&lt;/a&gt; by Jack London -- A novel set at the time of the 19th-century Klondike Gold Rush that explores a dog's return to his primal nature. This book was a very short and enjoyable read and has a &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Call-Wild-ebook/dp/B0083ZBW2Y/"&gt;free Kindle edition&lt;/a&gt; (as well as many other free editions, such as &lt;a href="http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/215"&gt;this one on Project Gutenberg&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 13:39:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-05-26:2013-05-26/iotw-may-20-2013.html</guid><category>iotw</category></item><item><title>Pelican-Gist Plugin</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-05-14/pelican-gist-plugin.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Today I created &lt;a href="https://github.com/kfr2/pelican-gist"&gt;Pelican-Gist&lt;/a&gt;, a small plugin for Pelican that allows the user to easily embed a &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/"&gt;Gist&lt;/a&gt; within his articles. You can see the source of the plugin below. If you'd like, you can also view the &lt;a href="https://github.com/kfr2/kfr2.github.com/blob/source/content/blog/2013/pelican-gist.md"&gt;Markdown source&lt;/a&gt; of this page to see how the plugin is triggered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/kfr2/5580453.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you find it useful.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 19:58:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-05-14:2013-05-14/pelican-gist-plugin.html</guid><category>meta</category><category>github</category><category>writing</category><category>python</category></item><item><title>Items of the Week: May 6, 2013</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-05-11/iotw-may-6-2013.html</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/bigcompany/know-your-http"&gt;Know Your HTTP!&lt;/a&gt; -- If you're looking for some informational posters for your home or office, Know Your HTTP offers a collection of posters describing HTTP methods, status codes, and headers. As an added bonus, the posters are licensed under the &lt;a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/"&gt;Creative Commons BY-NC-SA&lt;/a&gt; so they may be transformed and shared as long as they're used for noncommercial purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/cafarm/aqua-theme"&gt;Aqua Theme&lt;/a&gt; -- Aqua Theme is a UI theme for &lt;a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/2"&gt;Sublime Text 2&lt;/a&gt; with a goal of making the application feel more native on OS X. It comes with both light and dark variations as well as four syntax highlighting color schemes (Espresso Aqua, Tomorrow Aqua, Monokai Aqua, and Tomorrow Night Aqua).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/dotless-de/vagrant-vbguest"&gt;vagrant-vbguest&lt;/a&gt; -- I really love &lt;a href="http://www.vagrantup.com/"&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt;, a tool that allows one to easily create complete development environments via virtual machines. It's very useful because, among other reasons, it lets the user create an environment that will be totally isolated from others. Vagrant-vbguest is a plugin for Vagrant which "automatically installs the host's VirtualBox Guest Additions on the guest system" upon boot of the VM. It's very useful because issues may arise if the Guest Additions versions do not match across host and guest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tryfoundation.io"&gt;Try Foundation&lt;/a&gt; -- Try Foundation provides interactive lessons designed to assist the user in learning &lt;a href="http://foundation.zurb.com/"&gt;ZURB Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, a front-end HTML/CSS framework analogous to &lt;a href="http://twitter.github.io/bootstrap/"&gt;Twitter Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;. The lessons include inline code editing with automatically updated output as well as many examples from which one can glean information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.unrealengine.com/html5/"&gt;Epic Citadel HTML5&lt;/a&gt; -- Epic Citadel is a demonstration of the &lt;a href="http://www.unrealengine.com/en/"&gt;Unreal Engine&lt;/a&gt; ported to HTML5 via WebGL and JavaScript (with benefits from &lt;a href="http://asmjs.org/"&gt;asm.js&lt;/a&gt;, a very optimized subset of JavaScript). The site recommends you run the demo in &lt;a href="http://nightly.mozilla.org/"&gt;Firefox Nightly&lt;/a&gt;, although I've had no issues with &lt;a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/channel/#aurora"&gt;Firefox Aurora&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Throne-Crescent-Moon-Kingdoms-ebook/dp/B0064VQDHI/"&gt;Throne of the Crescent Moon&lt;/a&gt; -- This sword-and-sorcery novel has interesting characters with a rich setting. I look forward to exploring it more during the upcoming week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 13:07:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-05-11:2013-05-11/iotw-may-6-2013.html</guid><category>iotw</category></item><item><title>Items of the Week: April 22, 2013</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-04-28/iotw-april-22-2013.html</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="maebert.github.io/jrnl/"&gt;Jrnl&lt;/a&gt; -- Jrnl is "[…] a simple journal application for your command line" written in Python that saves to text files and &lt;a href="http://dayoneapp.com/"&gt;Day One&lt;/a&gt; journals. According to the site, "a journal helps you to keep track of the things you get done and how you did them" and a good starting place is to make a habit of writing at least 20 words per day. I've been using &lt;a href="http://brettterpstra.com/projects/nvalt/"&gt;nvALT&lt;/a&gt; to maintain my work journal over the past year but have found it sometimes inconveniencing to switch to the nvALT window when I want to compose. Because I spend a large majority of my time with a terminal as the focused window, I believe I'm going to see if jrnl works better. To setup jrnl with my Day One journal, I had to add the following to the journals object of my &lt;code&gt;.jrnl&lt;/code&gt; configuration file:  &lt;code&gt;"default": "/Users/kevin/Dropbox/Apps/Day One/Journal.dayone"&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://taskwarrior.org/projects/show/taskwarrior"&gt;Taskwarrior&lt;/a&gt; -- Although &lt;a href="https://trello.com/"&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; is a wonderful tool I've been greatly appreciating for quite some time (especially to track work tasks in Kanban-like fashion), I often find myself wanting a much simpler list tool for my personal tasks and quick notes. From what I can tell based off my usage of it over the past week, Taskwarrior fulfills my requirements very well. Installation on OS X is very easy:  merely install &lt;a href="http://mxcl.github.io/homebrew/"&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; and run &lt;code&gt;brew install task&lt;/code&gt;. For more information, check out its &lt;a href="http://taskwarrior.org/projects/taskwarrior/wiki/30-second_Tutorial"&gt;30-second tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="fargo.io/"&gt;Fargo&lt;/a&gt; -- Fargo is a lovely web-based outliner from &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dave_Winer"&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.kyleshank.com/"&gt;Kyle Shank&lt;/a&gt; that syncs with Dropbox. I need to look more into this over the upcoming week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.thehikeguy.com/2011/11/10/pct-moleskines/"&gt;My Pacific Crest Trail Moleskine Journals&lt;/a&gt; -- In this blog entry from 2011, the author shares a multitude of image scans and stories from the journals he kept while hiking the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pacific_Crest_Trail"&gt;Pacific Crest Trail&lt;/a&gt;. It's intriguing to see how the author's journals change over time as he learns what information he desires to track the most. I also appreciate how he shares his reasoning for keeping the journals:  "I would use my journal to define problems I would experience on the trail and come up with options for trying to solve the problem. […] Keeping a journal helps me define my main goal as well as daily goals I would make."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 20:09:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-04-28:2013-04-28/iotw-april-22-2013.html</guid><category>iotw</category></item><item><title>Items of the Week: April 15, 2013</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-04-22/iotw-april-15-2013.html</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://nathanmarz.com/blog/you-should-blog-even-if-you-have-no-readers.html"&gt;You should blog even if you have no readers&lt;/a&gt; -- Two main reasons: writing makes you a better reader and writing makes you smarter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://forecast.io"&gt;Forecast&lt;/a&gt; -- A beautiful and incredibly functional weather web app that is very likely the (best) mobile weather application. The "installation process" for iOS is incredibly easy in Safari: you merely load forecast.io in Safari and follow the instructions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://artpolikarpov.github.io/garmoshka/"&gt;Garmoshka&lt;/a&gt; -- Resize your browser window to "play" the accordion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://song-of-github.herokuapp.com/"&gt;Song of GitHub&lt;/a&gt; -- Convert a person's GitHub commit history into a MIDI using &lt;a href="http://mudcu.be/midi-js/"&gt;MIDI.js&lt;/a&gt;. For an example, check out &lt;a href="http://song-of-github.herokuapp.com/?username=kfr2"&gt;my Song of GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/3ds/features/"&gt;Nintendo 3DS XL&lt;/a&gt; -- Although I greatly enjoyed the regular 3DS, the XL's matte finish feels and looks fantastic (and doesn't get incredibly covered with fingerprints to boot). The increased screen sizes are also very appealing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 20:18:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-04-22:2013-04-22/iotw-april-15-2013.html</guid><category>iotw</category></item><item><title>Items of the Week: April 8, 2013</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-04-15/iotw-april-8-2013.html</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://education.10gen.com/courses/10gen/M101P/2013_April/about"&gt;MongoDB for Developers&lt;/a&gt; -- A free MOOC offering an introduction to &lt;a href="http://www.mongodb.org/"&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt; using Python. &lt;a href="http://www.10gen.com/about"&gt;10gen&lt;/a&gt;, the company behind MongoDB, hosts the course on the &lt;a href="http://edx.org/"&gt;EdX platform&lt;/a&gt;. The course has great pacing and doesn't take much time throughout the week to complete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://http://starlogs.net"&gt;Starlogs&lt;/a&gt; -- This website converts GitHub commit messages into scrolling text à la the introduction to each Star Wars movie. For instance, you may enjoy &lt;a href="http://starlogs.net/#django/django"&gt;Django's Starlogs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/shower/shower/"&gt;Shower Presentation Engine&lt;/a&gt; -- An HTML presentation/slideshow engine similar to &lt;a href="http://lab.hakim.se/reveal-js/"&gt;reveal.js&lt;/a&gt;. The project's GitHub page offers &lt;a href="https://github.com/shower/shower/#usage-examples"&gt;numerous examples&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 20:36:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-04-15:2013-04-15/iotw-april-8-2013.html</guid><category>iotw</category></item><item><title>Items of the Week: April 1, 2013</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-04-07/iotw-april-1-2013.html</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.manning.com/rathore/"&gt;Clojure in Action&lt;/a&gt; by Amit Rathore. I've found this book much easier to read and understand than both &lt;a href="http://www.clojurebook.com/"&gt;Clojure Programming&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://pragprog.com/book/shcloj/programming-clojure"&gt;Programming Clojure&lt;/a&gt; as it seems to offer a much better high-level explanations of the language and how it fits into the JVM ecosystem. However, I've not yet made significant progress into any of the books (and am quite new with Clojure) so take my thoughts with quite a few grains of salt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.adobe.com/devnet/html5/articles/angularjs-directives-and-the-computer-science-of-javascript.html"&gt;AngularJS Directives and The Computer Science of JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; -- This article offers a nice introduction to &lt;a href="http://docs.angularjs.org/guide/directive"&gt;AngularJS's directives&lt;/a&gt;, a way to "teach HTML new tricks." In layman's terms, a directive "[…] is a way for you to define a new HTML element or attribute." Angular will then execute the directive's code when the element or attribute is found.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://latentflip.com/imperative-vs-declarative/"&gt;Imperative vs Declarative&lt;/a&gt; -- An explanation of imperative vs. declarative programming paradigms. Imperative programming is telling the machine &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to do something and declarative programmign is telling the machine &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you would like to happen and allowing it to figure out the specific steps. It uses map/reduce functions, SQL, and d3.js to discuss how declarative programming abstracts away the specifics the programmer will focus on while using imperative programming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.zelda.com/skywardsword/"&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Skyward Sword&lt;/a&gt; -- I am absolutely loving this game except for how it continually reminds the player of the function of items she just picked up…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 20:08:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-04-07:2013-04-07/iotw-april-1-2013.html</guid><category>iotw</category></item><item><title>Items of the Week: March 25, 2013</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-03-31/iotw-march-25-2013.html</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://typedarray.org/javascript-refresh/"&gt;A JavaScript Refresh&lt;/a&gt; -- A lengthy overview of JavaScript and some of its idiosyncrasies broken down into easily digestible sections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://burakkanber.com/blog/machine-learning-in-other-languages-introduction/"&gt;Machine Learning in JavaScript: Introduction&lt;/a&gt; -- Overviews of the following fundamental machine learning algorithms using JavaScript:  k-nearest-neighbor, k-means clustering, Genetic algorithms, Naive Bayes classifier, Neural network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://usablica.github.com/intro.js/"&gt;Intro.js&lt;/a&gt; -- A small JavaScript library offering "better introductions for websites and features with a step-by-step guide for your projects."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://devgirl.org/2013/03/21/fun-with-angularjs/"&gt;Fun with AngularJS!&lt;/a&gt; -- An overview of AngularJS using &lt;a href="http://devgirl.org/files/MediaExplorer/#/"&gt;an iTunes Media Search application&lt;/a&gt; the author created. The author also has a great list of further resources at the end of her post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.jeffknupp.com/blog/2013/02/14/drastically-improve-your-python-understanding-pythons-execution-model/"&gt;Understanding Python's Execution Model&lt;/a&gt; -- In this article, the author helps "[…] you understand what's happening behind the scenes when you do common things like creating a variable or calling a function" in Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.miguelgrinberg.com/post/the-flask-mega-tutorial-part-i-hello-world"&gt;The Flask Mega-Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; -- A series of tutorials where the author builds a microblog engine using &lt;a href="http://flask.pocoo.org/"&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt;, a micro web framework for Python. The tutorials include creating templates and forms, interacting with a database, unit testing the code, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://gdc2013.nintendo.com/"&gt;Nintendo Web Framework&lt;/a&gt; -- "The Nintendo Web Framework is a development environment based on WebKit technologies, supporting application development on the Wii U system using HTML5, JavaScript, and CSS." Although not much information is presently available, I'm pretty excited to see what comes of this framework in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 21:19:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-03-31:2013-03-31/iotw-march-25-2013.html</guid><category>iotw</category></item><item><title>Items of the Week: March 18, 2013</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-03-25/iotw-march-18-2013.html</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.artlogic.com/2013/03/06/angularjs-for-jquery-developers/"&gt;AngularJS for jQuery Developers&lt;/a&gt; -- A very brief introduction to &lt;a href="http://angularjs.org"&gt;AngularJS&lt;/a&gt;. I particularly enjoyed its Dependency Injection overview.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://superherojs.com/"&gt;Superhero.js&lt;/a&gt; -- "[…] a continously updated list of articles that help explain the syntax of JavaScript, how to organize your projects, how to test your code, and what's on the horizon."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Effective-JavaScript-Specific-Software-Development/dp/0321812182/"&gt;Effective JavaScript&lt;/a&gt; -- This book offers concise and digestible pieces of advice on JavaScript development. I highly recommend it if you'd like to further your understanding of the language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/Mikkeren/FizzBuzzEnterpriseEdition"&gt;FizzBuzz Enterprise Edition&lt;/a&gt; -- …yep…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_to_Live_on_24_Hours_a_Day"&gt;How to Live on 24 Hours a Day&lt;/a&gt; -- Advice on how to live and not merely exist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magic: the Gathering &lt;a href="https://www.wizards.com/Magic/Magazine/Article.aspx?x=mtg/daily/eventcoverage/gppit13/welcome"&gt;Grand Prix Pittsburgh 2013&lt;/a&gt; -- A stellar event for one of the world's greatest games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 16:21:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-03-25:2013-03-25/iotw-march-18-2013.html</guid><category>iotw</category></item><item><title>Items of the Week: March 11, 2013</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-03-17/iotw-march-11-2013.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I've decided to start creating a weekly post describing the websites or other items I've found interesting over the past week. Although the majority of items will likely be websites (as they are often the most easily accessible kind of items), I may mention books, applications, video games, or anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.trello.com/trello-for-ipad-is-here/"&gt;Trello for iPad is Here!&lt;/a&gt; -- The incredibly useful board- and list-based information management tool now has an iPad application. It looks fantastic but has a few oddities on iPad mini (such as a card's edit description field appearing below the on-screen keyboard).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://davidseah.com/blog/2012/08/trello-again-followup/"&gt;Trello Again:  Followup&lt;/a&gt; -- An examination of &lt;a href="http://davidseah.com/"&gt;David Seah&lt;/a&gt;'s personal Trello workflow. He seems to advocate keeping all personal items on one board so as to not lose track of items spanning multiple boards. Furthermore, I enjoy his idea of prepending unplanned items with a "+" sign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.thoughtbot.com/"&gt;Thoughtbot&lt;/a&gt;'s &lt;a href="https://github.com/thoughtbot/guides/tree/master/product-management/trello"&gt;Process management with Trello guide&lt;/a&gt; -- Over the past four months, I've been trying to revamp my team's (essentially non-existent) style of project management to something resembling [Kanban](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kanban_(development) because we serve in an operational role and work on many projects simulataneously. Originally, we followed &lt;a href="https://community.uservoice.com/blog/trello-google-docs-product-management/"&gt;the Trello workflow used by Uservoice&lt;/a&gt; and found it generally worked well. However, I've felt it lacked a good place to note technical improvements/refactorings that had to be made (such as upgrading a site from Django 1.3 to 1.4) as well as a good review process. Thoughtbot's guide to its Trello workflow solves many of the issues I've had with my team's current Trello implementation and seems like it will work much better for my team's structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.fogcreek.com/the-trello-tech-stack/"&gt;The Trello Tech Stack&lt;/a&gt; -- Brett Kiefer describes the front-end and back-end technologies used to create Trello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://omniti.com/seeds/your-code-may-be-elegant"&gt;Your Code May Be Elegant&lt;/a&gt;
 -- "Your code may be elegant, but if it doesn't meet the objectives (be they time or business) it doesn't f***ing work." Although it is interesting and exciting to build the most robust solution possible, it is more important to consider the business contraints of time and money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://timepiece.inostudio.de/"&gt;Timepiece Rounded&lt;/a&gt; -- An OpenType-font which displays time strings (like 17:23:25) as a clock glyph. Fonts can define &lt;a href="http://alistapart.com/article/the-era-of-symbol-fonts"&gt;custom ligatures&lt;/a&gt;, a sequence of characters, that are replaced with a single glyph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://java.ociweb.com/mark/clojure/article.html"&gt;Clojure - Functional Programming for the JVM&lt;/a&gt; -- "[…] a fairly comprehensive introduction to the Clojure programming language."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.one-tab.com/"&gt;OneTab&lt;/a&gt; -- A neat Chrome extension that converts all your tabs to a list within a page (and then back again).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://mediaqueri.es"&gt;Media Queries&lt;/a&gt; -- "A collection of inspirational websites using media queries and responsive web design." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://craphound.com/ftw/"&gt;For the Win&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="http://craphound.com/"&gt;Cory Doctorow&lt;/a&gt; -- A novel in which gold farmers struggle to bring better working conditions to themselves and all workers around the world. This was an incredibly fun and engaging book that will have the reader pondering the conditions of life in third world countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 12:14:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-03-17:2013-03-17/iotw-march-11-2013.html</guid><category>iotw</category></item><item><title>Creating A Pelican-Powered Site on GitHub Pages</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-02-03/creating-a-pelican-powered-site-on-github-pages.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Prologue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As stated in &lt;a href="http://magically.us/2013-01-01/hello-world.html"&gt;my "Hello World" post&lt;/a&gt;, magically.us is created with &lt;a href="http://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; &amp;mdash; a static website generator &amp;mdash; and hosted on &lt;a href="http://pages.github.com/"&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. Benefits of static websites are abundant. This combination allows one to easily update the look and feel of a website as well as its content while maintaining a complete revision history through the &lt;a href="http://git-scm.com/"&gt;Git version control system&lt;/a&gt;. Static websites are awesome because they allow one to maintain a copy of her content and not worry about the "walled garden" effects of sites like Facebook wherein content can be challenging to export to other platforms. Generators are incredibly useful because they allow one to separate her content from her presentation templates. Because static websites are HTML and related assets, it is incredibly easy to move one's site to other webhosts as is necessary or desired. Another nicety exists in that GitHub Pages also provides the URI &lt;code&gt;http://username.github.com&lt;/code&gt; and optionally allows the user to use her own domain. Static website generators (like Pelican) generally allow one to write content in lightweight markup languages (like &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown"&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ReStructuredText"&gt;reStructuredText&lt;/a&gt;) that is translated to HTML as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post introduces how I maintain this website and (hopefully) provides the reader a starting place for her own experimentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Assumptions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You're using a Unix-like environment and are comfortable using a command-line terminal and shell. If you're using Windows, you may want to examine my &lt;a href="https://github.com/kfr2/python-web-dev-box"&gt;python web-dev box&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href="http://vagrantup.com"&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; virtual machine, to provide this environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have Python, &lt;a href="http://www.virtualenv.org/en/latest/"&gt;virtualenv&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.doughellmann.com/projects/virtualenvwrapper/"&gt;virtualenvwrapper&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://pypi.python.org/pypi/pip"&gt;pip&lt;/a&gt; installed on your machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have installed Git and have created a &lt;a href="http://github.com"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; account. I furthermore assume you have working knowledge of Git. &lt;a href="https://help.github.com/"&gt;GitHub's help pages&lt;/a&gt; may prove useful for many questions you may have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/kfr2/kfr2.github.com/fork"&gt;Fork my kfr2.github.com repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Underneath the repository's settings, rename the forked repository to &lt;code&gt;your_username.github.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open a terminal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone the repository to your machine with the command &lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/your_username/your_username.github.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a new virtualenv for the project by running &lt;code&gt;mkvirtualenv your_username.github.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;cd your_username.github.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;setvirtualenvproject&lt;/code&gt; to established &lt;code&gt;your_username.github.com&lt;/code&gt; as the virtualenv's default directory. When you next run &lt;code&gt;workon your_username.github.com&lt;/code&gt; to load the virtualenv, your shell will change its working directory to the &lt;code&gt;your_username.github.com&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;git checkout source&lt;/code&gt; to see the site's source files (rather than its compiled HTML files).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install the project's requirements:  &lt;code&gt;pip install -r requirements.txt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Configuration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir themes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download &lt;a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-themes"&gt;a Pelican theme&lt;/a&gt; and place it within a subdirectory of &lt;code&gt;themes&lt;/code&gt;. For instance, you can download &lt;a href="https://github.com/kfr2/pelican-svbtle"&gt;my site's theme&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/kfr2/pelican-svbtle.git your_username.github.com/themes/pelican-svbtle&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update the settings within &lt;code&gt;pelicanconf.py&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;publishconf.py&lt;/code&gt;. You may find Pelican's &lt;a href="http://docs.getpelican.com/en/3.1.1/settings.html"&gt;settings documentation&lt;/a&gt; helpful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update content within &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt;'s subdirectories. For instance, you will likely want to delete any entries underneath &lt;code&gt;content/blog&lt;/code&gt; as well as modify &lt;code&gt;content/extra&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;content/pages&lt;/code&gt; to your liking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you'd like to serve this site at something other than &lt;code&gt;your_username.github.com&lt;/code&gt;, update &lt;code&gt;content/extra/CNAME&lt;/code&gt; to include the desired domain. See GitHub's "&lt;a href="https://help.github.com/articles/setting-up-a-custom-domain-with-pages"&gt;Setting up a custom domain with Pages&lt;/a&gt;" for further instructions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you wish to run a development server to view your site and its changes, run the command &lt;code&gt;make devserver&lt;/code&gt;. The site should be accessible at &lt;a href="http://localhost:8000"&gt;http://localhost:8000&lt;/a&gt;. The development server can be stopped with the command &lt;code&gt;./develop_server.sh stop&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When satisfied, commit your changes: &lt;code&gt;git commit -am "A description of your changes."&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push your source file changes: &lt;code&gt;git push origin source&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;make github&lt;/code&gt; to push your compiled source files to GitHub. You will likely receive an email notification regarding your page's build status.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;General Workflow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;workon your_username.github.com&lt;/code&gt; to activate the project's virtualenv.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;python new_post.py&lt;/code&gt; to create a new post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit the post in your favorite text editor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Examine the post in context of your website with &lt;code&gt;make devserver&lt;/code&gt;. Shut the server down with &lt;code&gt;./develop_server.sh stop&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When satisfied with the post, run &lt;code&gt;git commit -am "Message describing the post"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push the source changes with &lt;code&gt;git push origin source&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push compiled files to your website with &lt;code&gt;make github&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Interesting Alternatives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My suggested workflow may not suit your needs or interests. Indeed, throughout the course of writing this post I realized how tedious it may be to setup a website using the methods outlined above &amp;mdash; especially if one is unfamiliar with Git, GitHub, *nix, or Python. Thus, you may be interested in examining how the alternatives listed below fit your needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;GitHub Pages Automatic Page Generator&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub allows one to &lt;a href="https://help.github.com/articles/creating-pages-with-the-automatic-generator"&gt;create pages with an automatic generator&lt;/a&gt; for both her user (at &lt;code&gt;http://username.github.com&lt;/code&gt;) and individual projects (at &lt;code&gt;http://username.github.com/project-name&lt;/code&gt;). This could be much less maintenance than a Pelican-based approach as GitHub hosts &lt;a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll"&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, the static website generator powering the automatic generator, and runs your site files through it when you push changes to the repository. In this situation, one will not need to have Python and the various Pelican dependencies installed. You may wish to view &lt;a href="http://magically.us/apg-test/"&gt;an example of Automatic Page Generator&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;gist.io&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://gist.io"&gt;gist.io&lt;/a&gt; allows one to create posts via &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/"&gt;Gists&lt;/a&gt;, a GitHub feature that allows one to easily store snippets of code or text and change them over time. Gist.io's homepage describes how one may use it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;1&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Create&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;gist&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;on&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Github&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;one&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;more&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Markdown&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;syntax&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;files&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
2&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Note&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;gist&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;ID&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;number&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;It&lt;/span&gt;’&lt;span class="n"&gt;s&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;usually&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;longish&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;number&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;like&lt;/span&gt; 29388372&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
3&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;View&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;your&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;writing&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;presented&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;nicely&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;at&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;gist&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;io&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;gist&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;here&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For reference, see the &lt;a href="http://gist.io/3135754"&gt;gist.io's example post&lt;/a&gt;. This method of content creation is incredibly rapid. However, it is designed for one-off posts as it does not currently provide a method for viewing multiple posts by the same author. If you like this style of content creation and wish gist.io acted more like a regular blog engine (as well as allowed you to customize its appearance), it may be worth forking &lt;a href="https://github.com/idan/gistio"&gt;gist.io's source&lt;/a&gt; into something that links to your gists and hosting it on a service like &lt;a href="http://heroku.com"&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this article has enlightened you to how you may use a static website generator like Pelican to share your content with the world. No matter which generator you use to convert your writings to web pages, they will function similarly and should all serve to assist you in conveying your messages to the world. May your journeys be fruitful and intriguing.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-02-03:2013-02-03/creating-a-pelican-powered-site-on-github-pages.html</guid><category>meta</category><category>github</category><category>blogging</category></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>http://magically.us/2013-01-01/hello-world.html</link><description>&lt;h3&gt;Prologue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good day to you, dear reader!  Welcome to magically.us, the personal website of &lt;a href="http://github.com/kfr2"&gt;Kevin Richardson&lt;/a&gt;, a software engineer and developer of web experiences.  Herein I will write about various things I find interesting as well as any revelations I have while developing different pieces of software or user experiences.  Although I currently work predominantly as a web developer (mostly with the lovely &lt;a href="http://djangoproject.com"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; framework), my personal and business work touches upon many facets and technologies.  Thus, my posts will not be strictly related to web development but may be very exploratory in nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The technology behind this site&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site is powered by &lt;a href="http://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; -- a static website generator  -- and is &lt;a href="https://github.com/kfr2/kfr2.github.com"&gt;hosted on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href="http://pages.github.com/"&gt;GitHub pages&lt;/a&gt;.  Content is written in &lt;a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/"&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;, a lightweight markup language that allows one to easily add syntax like headings, anchors, and lists to a page.  I use OSX and &lt;a href="http://mouapp.com/"&gt;Mou&lt;/a&gt;, the "missing Markdown editor for web developers", to develop and write the various content contained on this site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you desire your own personal site, I highly recommend a similar setup as the workflow for adding content to this site is quite easy if you are familiar with GitHub and Python.  If you're not (and desire to setup a similar website), fret not -- I will soon write a post describing how one can setup her own installation of Pelican with GitHub pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Epilogue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you very much for perusing my small corner of the web.  If you already haven't, you may be interested in viewing &lt;a href="/pages/projects.html"&gt;a list of my projects&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://github.com/kfr2"&gt;my GitHub account&lt;/a&gt;.  Furthermore, please feel free to contact me using the methods listed in &lt;a href="/humans.txt"&gt;my humans.txt file&lt;/a&gt; as I would love to discuss Life, the Universe, and Everything with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pax et bonum: peace and good.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Kevin Richardson</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 19:55:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>tag:magically.us,2013-01-01:2013-01-01/hello-world.html</guid><category>meta</category><category>github</category><category>writing</category><category>python</category></item></channel></rss>